and at the end of every sprint, they organize a demo session to share the output of what they've done, transparently. And every day, each member of the team gives an update of what they are working on individually. Now, all this transparency can be uncomfortable for people, because suddenly, there is no place to hide anymore. Everything we do is transparent for everyone. So, alignment is not easy, and providing autonomy is not so obvious, either. One executive at another company likes to explain how he used to be a master of milestone-tracking. Now, today, to know how things are going, instead of looking at status reports, he needs to walk down to the team floors to attend one of their sessions. And instead of telling people what to do, he looks for ways to help them.
y al final de cada iteración se organiza una reunión de demostración para compartir los resultados de lo que hicieron, con transparencia. Y todos los días, cada miembro del equipo informa lo que están haciendo de manera individual. Toda esta transparencia puede resultar incómoda para algunos, porque de repente ya no hay lugar para ocultarse. Todo lo que hacemos es transparente para todos. Conseguir la alineación es complicado y brindar autonomía no es algo tan obvio tampoco. A un ejecutivo en otra empresa le gusta hablar de cómo solía ser un experto en búsquedas. Ahora, para saber cómo van las cosas, en lugar de mirar los informes de estado, necesita ir a donde están los equipos y asistir a una de sus reuniones. Y en lugar de decir a las personas qué hacer, busca la manera como ayudarles.
That is radical change for someone who used to be a master of milestone-tracking. But in the old world, this executive said, "I only had the illusion of control. In reality, many projects would run over time and over budget, anyway. Now I have much more transparency, and I can course-correct much earlier if needed." And middle managers need to change as well. First of all, without the handovers and the PowerPoint, there's less of a need for middle managers. And in the old world, there was this idea of thinkers and doers. Employees would just follow orders. But now, instead of only managing other people, middle managers were expected to become player-coaches. So imagine, for the last 10 years, you have just been telling other people what to do, but now you're expected to do things yourself again. Clearly, this model is not for everyone, and some great people leave the company. But the result is a new culture with less hierarchy. And all of this is hard work. But it's worth it. The companies that I worked with, they were used to deploying new product features a few times per year. Now they have releases every few weeks, and without the handovers and the red tape, the whole organization becomes more efficient. And finally, if you walk the halls of these companies today, you just feel a new energy. It feels as if you're walking the halls of a very large start-up. Now, to be fair, these companies, they cannot claim victory yet. But at least with this new model, they are much better prepared to respond to change. The world is getting faster and more complex, so we need to reboot our way of working. And the hardest part of that change is not in structure or process or procedure, and it's also not just senior executives taking charge. Leaders will be all of those in the organization who embrace the change. We all have to lead the change. So the question is: What are you willing to give up? Thank you. (Applause)
Es un cambio enorme para alguien que solía ser un experto de las búsquedas. "Antes", dijo el ejecutivo, "solo tenía la ilusión del control. En la realidad, muchos proyectos se quedan sin tiempo y sin presupuesto. Ahora hay mucha más transparencia, y puedo corregir el curso del proyecto antes, si es necesario". Y los directivos intermedios deben cambiar también. Primero, sin las entregas y sin el PowerPoint, no son tan necesarios los directivos intermedios. Antes, existía la idea de que había pensadores y realizadores. Los empleados solo seguían ordenes. Ahora, en lugar de solo supervisar a otras personas, se espera que los directivos intermedios sean entrenadores. Imaginen que en los últimos 10 años, le han estado diciendo a otros qué hacer, y ahora se espera que hagan las cosas por su cuenta otra vez. Es claro que este modelo no es para todos, y muchas personas dejan la empresa. Pero el resultado es una nueva cultura con menos jerarquía. Para esto se necesita mucho trabajo. Pero vale la pena. Las empresas con las que he trabajado, solían introducir características nuevas a un producto algunas veces al año. Ahora hacen lanzamientos cada par de semanas, y sin las entregas y la cinta roja, la organización se vuelve más eficiente. Y finalmente, si ahora caminas por los pasillos de estas empresas, sientes una nueva energía. Se siente como caminar por los pasillos de un gran emprendimiento. Ahora bien, estas empresas, no pueden cantar victoria aún. Pero por lo menos con este nuevo modelo, están mejor preparadas para enfrentar el cambio. El mundo es cada vez más rápido y más complejo, por eso necesitamos reiniciar nuestra forma de trabajar. Y lo más difícil de ese cambio no es la estructura, ni el proceso o el procedimiento. Y tampoco se trata de los altos ejecutivos tomando el mando. Los líderes serán aquellos en la organización que acepten el cambio. Todos debemos liderar el cambio. Así que, la pregunta es: ¿Qué estás dispuesto a abandonar? Gracias. (Aplausos)